{"tossups": [{"question": "As aide-de-camp to Robert E. Lee, this man delivered the surrender ultimatum to John Brown before the latter was captured at Harpers Ferry. During the Peninsular Campaign, this man, who was known for his \u201ccavalier\u201d image, conducted the \u201cRide around McClellan.\u201d This man was mortally wounded at the Battle of Yellow Tavern and was known as the \u201ceyes and ears\u201d of his army. For ten points, name this Confederate general who commanded the cavalry of the Army of Northern Virginia.", "answer": "J(ames) E(well) B(rown) \u201cJeb\u201d<b> Stuart</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This man led an expedition in which men in<em> testudo</em> formation could not advance to meet the enemy Parthian horse archers. This man was executed by having molten gold poured down his throat to represent his wealth. Before his defeat at Carrhae, this leader crucified several thousand people after successfully defeating the revolt of Spartacus. For ten points, name this enormously rich Roman general who was a member of the First Triumvirate alongside Pompey and Caesar.", "answer": "Marcus Licinius<b> Crassus</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "This country\u2019s leader banned the Birilik opposition party and may have kidnapped his own nephew, Jamshid. Hundreds of protestors in this country were massacred in Bobur Square in 2005 in Andijan. That massacre in this country was supposed retribution against the Islamist Hizb-ut Tahrir. British ambassador Craig Murray claims that two dissidents in this country were boiled alive by its president, Islam Karimov. For ten points, name this member of the Commonwealth of Independent States.", "answer": "Republic of<b> Uzbekistan</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Deadly riots during the grand opening of this location inspired a similar structure, designed by Renzo Piano, to be placed on an artificial island. Goryo Farm was absorbed during the construction of this location which was the subject of the decade-long Sanrizuka Struggle. Construction on this location began after projections predicting that Haneda Airport would reach capacity by 1970. Japan Airlines has its main hub at, for ten points, what international airport serving Tokyo?", "answer": "<b> Narita</b> International Airport (accept<b> Narita</b> Kokusai Kuko; accept Tokyo<b> Narita</b> Airport; accept<b> New Tokyo International</b> Airport; accept<b> Shin Tokyo Kokusai</b> Kuko; accept<b> NRT</b>; accept <b>RJAA</b>) Page 1", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Architecture"}, {"question": "Estes Kefauver introduced the bill that called for this amendment, which dealt with a body introduced in Article II, Section 1 of the Constitution. Other than Minnesota, the central region in question in this amendment was the only source of electoral votes for Walter Mondale in 1980. A Home Rule Act established the office of mayor in the area affected by this amendment. For ten points, name this 1961 amendment that provided voting rights to the District of Columbia.", "answer": "<b> 23</b>rd Amendment", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "Marshal W.F. Degan was murdered during this event, at which the sniper Lon Horiuchi controversially killed the central target\u2019s pregnant wife Vicki. Culminating in the arrest of Kevin Harris and former Green Beret, Randy Weaver, this event and a similar event the following year involving David Koresh\u2019s Branch Davidian Compound in Waco were sources of inspiration for the perpetrators of the Oklahoma City bombing. For ten points, name this eleven-day siege in 1992 in Idaho.", "answer": "<b> Ruby Ridge</b> Siege (accept answers including \u201cStandoff,\u201d \u201cIncident,\u201d etc.)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "The most extreme members of this group sat on the highest seats of the National Assembly and were named \u201cThe Mountain.\u201d C.L.R. James wrote a book titled for \u201cBlack\u201d members of this group, one of whose leaders was killed by the \u201cAngel of Assassination,\u201d Charlotte Corday. This faction set up the Committee of Public Safety but fell in the Thermidorian Reaction. For ten points, name this faction in the French Revolution led by Maximilien Robespierre.", "answer": "<b> Jacobin</b>s (accept Black<b> Jacobin</b>s)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "Defiance of an early version of this law led to a mass migration to Cass County, Michigan.<em> Prigg v</em> <em>Pennsylvania</em> greatly weakened that early version of this law. The Wisconsin Supreme Court\u2019s refusal to enforce this law was ruled unconstitutional in<em> Ableman v Booth</em>. This act was called the \u201cBloodhound Law\u201d by abolitionists. For ten points name this act, part of the Compromise of 1850, that required Northerners to return runaway slaves to the South.", "answer": "<b> Fugitive Slave Act</b> of 1850", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "The handling of this storm improved George H.W. Bush\u2019s approval ratings in Dade County. For ten points, name this 1992 hurricane that heavily affected South Florida.", "answer": "Hurricane<b> Andrew</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "In this modern-day country, Maha Bandula led foot-soldiers during the Battle of Danubyu. Following the collapse of the Pagan Empire, the Myinsaing Kingdom ruled this country for seventeen years. This country\u2019s Arakan and Hanthawaddy kingdoms were conquered by its Toungoo Dynasty, whose official religion was Theravada Buddhism. King Mindon founded the city of Mandalay in, for ten points, what country, whose kingdoms fought over the Irrawaddy Valley?", "answer": "Republic of the Union of<b> Myanmar</b> (accept Union of<b> Burma</b>, accept Pyidaunzu Thanmada <b>Myama</b> Nainngandaw)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man noted, \u201cWe cannot all be Descartes or Kant, but we all want happiness\u201d in his essay, \u201cThe Path of the Law.\u201d This man\u2019s opinion in<em> Buck v. Bell</em>, supporting compulsory sterilization, came after a 1919 First Amendment case in which this man wrote about the \u201csubstantive evils\u201d caused by \u201cshouting fire in a crowded theater.\u201d For ten points, name this Supreme Court justice who outlined the doctrine of\u201cclear and present danger\u201d in the case<em> Schenck v. U.S.</em>", "answer": "Oliver Wendell<b> Holmes</b>, Jr.", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This thinker wrote that he felt \u201ca gentle, melancholy emotion\u201d while meditating in Michigan in his essay, \u201cTwo Weeks in the Wilderness.\u201d This man criticized the power of the legislative branch in a work he researched with Gustave de Beaumont while examining the prison system. In that work, this thinker wrote that fear arises from \u201csoft despotism\u201d and warned against a \u201ctyranny of the majority.\u201d For ten points, name this French author of<em> Democracy in America</em>.", "answer": "Alexis de<b> Tocqueville</b>", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Other Social Science"}, {}, {"question": "<b>A 1981 bill to make this man an honorary citizen of the United States was sponsored by Congressman Tom Lantos. This man studied architecture at the University of Michigan before he became an employee of a branch office of the Holland Bank in Haifa. This man was</b> <b>reported to have died in (+)</b> <b>Lubyanka two years after being arrested by the Soviets. This</b> <b>diplomat is believed to have been arrested due to his work for the (*)</b> CIA while in Budapest. For ten points, name this Swedish special envoy to Hungary who saved thousands of Jews during the Nazi occupation.", "answer": "Raoul<b> Wallenberg</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>Heinz Valk coined the name for these events, and one of the outcomes of these events was recognized by Iceland before any other nation. During these events, the 50</b><em>th</em><b>anniversary of the signing of the Molotov-Ribbentrop Pact led to a 2 million person (+) human chain. The epic hero</b><em><b> Lacplesis</b></em><b> inspired a rock opera popularized during this event that also included Alo Mattisen\u2019s \u201cFive Patriotic Songs\u201d at the (*) </b> Tartu Pop Festival. Lasting from roughly 1987 to 1991, for ten points, give the common name for a series of events that contributed to the independence of the Baltic states.", "answer": "<b> Singing Revolution</b>s", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>During this event, scholar Eduard Goldst\u00a8ucker tested one leader\u2019s commitment to the freedom of the press when he criticized President Anton\u00b4\u0131n Novotn\u00b4y on national television. During this event, journalist Ludv\u00b4\u0131k Vacul\u00b4\u0131k [VATS-oo-leek] released a manifesto called</b> <b>(+)</b> <b>\u201cTwo Thousand Words.\u201d In the aftermath of this event, Gustav Husak [HOO-shock]</b> <b>instituted the \u201cnormalization\u201d period. During this period, (*)</b> Alexander Dubcek [DOOB-check] tried to institute \u201cSocialism with a human face.\u201d For ten points, name this period of political liberalization and protests in the capital of Czechoslovakia.", "answer": "<b> Prague Spring</b> Page 10", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>Many of these events that started in Canada were led by the employees of Conrad Kohrs. In 1866, Nelson Story led one of these events that ended in Montana. These</b> <b>events greatly increased in number after Joseph (+)</b> <b>McCoy opened a facility in</b> <b>1867, and there was a higher demand for them after the Civil War when Armour and Company opened. Routes for carrying out these events included the (*) </b> Goodnight-Loving Trail and the Shawnee Trail. For ten points, name these events, some of which ended at the Abilene railhead on the Chisholm Trail.", "answer": "<b> Cattle drive</b>s (accept answers indicating the movement of<b> cattle</b> or<b> cow</b>s)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}